Andrew Messier

Software Engineer / Web Developer / Consultant

andrewmessier.com

Charlotte, NC, USA andrewgmessier@gmail.com 704.743.6265

linkedin.com/in/andrewgmessier github.com/messman

Software engineer with over a decade of web application development knowledge.

Experienced in building web products across roles: design, testing, management, development, and deploy. **Helping technology companies meet development challenges** by contributing expertise in code organization, technical debt management, development workflow, and product management.

Knowledge

TypeScript; React; styled-components; webpack; jQuery; Docker; CI/CD; npm package authoring; Node.js; Express; git; PostgreSQL; ASP.NET Core; Figma; Jira; Confluence; Azure DevOps; SCRUM

Experience

Contractor & Consultant 2020 - Present

- Modernizes engineering processes, including the synergy between engineering and other departments.
- Heads technical debt reduction efforts.

Senior Software Developer, Jackrabbit Technologies - Huntersville, NC

2018 - 2020

(Previous title: .NET Front End Web Developer, 2018 to 2019)

- Directed development team Scrum meetings on a stand-in basis as a Certified Scrum Master.
- Lead technical debt epics on behalf of Product and Engineering.
- Assisted in the modernization of the codebase by co-managing a shift to TypeScript and React.

Software Engineer, LEAD Technologies, Inc. - Charlotte, NC

2013 - 2018

(Previous title: Software Engineering Intern, 2013 to 2014)

- Responsible for multiple customer-facing single-page JavaScript web applications and a toolkit.
- Built web services for multiple platforms to bridge web applications with document processing.
- Optimized HTML5 Canvas-based web applications to reduce load and execution times by at least half.

Projects

Wells Beach Time - github.com/messman/tidy

2017 - Present

A mobile web app that displays information on sun, weather, and tides for the beach town of Wells, Maine so that residents (like my parents) and renters know when to visit the beach each day.

Developed & deployed with Docker; containerized Node.js web service that aggregates data from third-party APIs from NOAA and OpenWeather; Designed in Figma; Built with React, TypeScript, and styled-components.

More projects at andrewmessier.com.

Education

University of North Carolina - Chapel Hill, NC

Class of 2015

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science – Graduation With Distinction (3.70)

Teaching and tutoring experience in web programming.